Vijayalaxmi Shetty

Flat No 203, Jare corner building Presadan Housing Society, Chikhali Road Pimpari Chinchwad, Nigdi Dist – Pune, Maharashtra.

Email: vijaya_5571@rediffmail.com

Mob No: 09890582779

Carrier Objective:

An innovative & a solution driven HR professional with 8 years of work exposure, collaborating with business leaders to achieve corporate excellence & drive human resource initiatives. Exposure to various domains of Human resource helps to evaluate & modify core business processes with respect to the ever-changing environment

HR Skills

- 1) Recruitment
- 2) Joining Formalities
- 3) Induction and Training
- 4) Payroll Management
- 5) Leave Management
- 6) Employee Engagement
- 7) Statutory Compliances
- 8) PMS and Increment
- 9) Exit Formalities
- 10) Training and Development
- 11) Handling HR software and HRMS
- 12) Administrative
- 13) Industrial Relations
- 14) Compensation and Benefits
- 15) Performance Managements
- 16) Employee Safety
- 17) General Administration

Work Experience: 1

Sr.HR Executive, in UPSPL Integrated Services Pvt Ltd. Site - Skoda Auto Volkswagen India Pvt Ltd (1st July 2020 to till date)

Roles & Responsibilities

- Joining formalities, prepared ID card process.
- Prepration of Offer, Appointment, Reliving letter and Experience Letter to employees.
- Prepration data of Id card, E mail Id generating of new employees.
- Responsible for employee relation.
- Prepration of monthly manpower data and Vacant Position.
- Employee engagement.
- Payroll management and Payroll Process.
- Attendance, Leave and OT management
- Preparing Diwali Bonus working data.
- Prepare the monthly salary processing data.

- Every month update deduction details of salary advance.
- Prepare full and final settlement for resigning employees.
- PF Employees registration.
- ESIC Employees registrations
- Employees personal file maintaining.
- Daily manpower data maintaining.
- Transportation and Canteen coupons management.
- Disciplinary action record maintaining
- Recruitment and onboarding.
- Resolving employees queries regarding grievance
- Training & Development calendar to monitoring.
- Housekeeping and security controlling
- Industrial Relationship.

Work Experience: 2

HR Executive in Sodexo technical service Pvt. Ltd. Site: Fiat Auto India Pvt Ltd (08th Feb 2019 – 30th June 2020)

Roles and Responsibilities:

1) Recruitment and selection:

Using Naukri partial for job posting, mass mailing, screening the resume, taketelephonicand facetofaceinterview, updating interviewfeedback sheet, issuing offer letter, updating manpower consolidation report.

2) Joining Formalities:

Induction and introduction program, signing circular, issuing joining kit all required stationeries, employee-id and thumb impression, documents verification & personal files, update employee database & welcome mail issuing appointment letter.

3) Exit Formalities:

Conducting exit interviews of resigned employees. Resignation and termination letter approving with one-month notice period, reliving/Experience letter, full & final Settlement, updating the reliving/Terminated list

4) Pay roll calculation:

Maintaining all employees data in software. Maintaining monthly Statutory records Generating leaves and attendance record from software for importing in salary processing. Maintaining attendance and leave records, sanction leaves application, time record by manual and punching data, completion and processing of attendance data in attendance system, processing monthly attendance musters for employees, maintaining employee's personal files and records, communicating HR policies

5) Performance Appraisal:

Performance assessment in co-ordination with the HR head & departmental heads and issuing increments & promotions letters as per management's Decision.

6) HR events and celebration:

Coordinate with location in charge to organize festival and events, Birthday, Picnic and Quiz Contest celebration, rewards and recognition

7) Other HR activities:

Issuing warning letter, absenteeism and disciplinary. Policy implementation in consultation with HR Head. Preparing Organization Structure and updating Job description of employees. Maintaining all administrative activities like, Uniform, shoes and PPE'.

Work Experience: 3

HR Executive in Kothari Autolink Pvt. Ltd. (19th Feb 2015–9th Jan 2019)

Roles and Responsibilities:

- 1) Recruitment
- 2) On-boarding and Induction.
- 3) Maintaining Personal File.
- 4) Attendance Management.
- 5) General Administrartion.
- 6) Diciplinary Action.
- 7) Payroll Management.

Work Experience: 4

HR Recruiter in Mansi Enterprise Services (5th Oct 2014-16th Feb 2015)

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Handling recruitment for manufacturing domain, selection process and freezing the requirement.
- Helping seniors with screening & short listing the resumes, Follow up and feedback.
- Involving in conducting telephonic interviews, and salary negotiations.
- Filter Resume as per the Requirement from job portals like Naukri, Monster, Times job, shine, job indeed and Jobs ahead.
- Responsible for calling the candidates, who suit the requirements specified by our clients, decide on which client they best suit and accordingly coach them.
- Schedule telephonic & personal interview with candidate.
- Scheduling interviews & constant follow-up. Putting advertisement on Job Portals.
- Receiving and communicating feedback to the candidates and following up with the candidates till their joining.
- Conducting and coordinating the walk-in and interviews with the short listed candidates.
- Maintaining a database of candidates for future references update the review.
- Preparing daily and weekly recruitment status reports. Offering candidates and following up till joining.
- Screening & short listing of CVs, Interview Scheduling of the short listed candidates.

Work Experience: 5

HR &AdminExecutivein Ashish Enterprises (10thJuly 2013-19th July 2014)

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Recruitment
- Joining Formalities, Induction Offer Letter, appointment Letter issuing.
- Maintaining attendance data, Leave data, OT data.
- Salary Processing.
- Training & development.
- Exit formalities.

Key Skills and Management:

Good command over verbal and written communication skills.

Quick learner and ability meet deadlines.

Promoting solutions

Creating Innovative Ideas

Good leadership Quality.

Operating Microsoft word, Excel 2003, 2007, 2010.

Strengths:

Good command over verbal and written communication skills.

Ability to grasp things easily.

Good Problem solving and reasoning skills.

A team player and excellent ability to understand other's point of view.

Good spoken & written communication skills.

Strong interpersonal skills (Relationship building).

Experience in effectively utilizing web recruitment tools, personal database, networking through various groups and Websites, references and other non-conventional methods of resourcing.

Projects:

Project completed in Human Resource Management with Special reference to Employee job satisfaction.

Education:

MBA. In HR with Textile from DKTE Society Rajwada, Ichalkaranji with First class 65.86% in final year in Year 2013.

B.Sc. in Mathematics from Kasturabai Walchand College, Sangli with First class 60.00% in final year in Year 2009.

Extra-Curricular activities And Achievements:

- Achieving appreciate certificate month of March 2021 from UPSPL Integrated Services Pvt Ltd
- Achieving appreciate certificate month of December 2020 from UPSPL integrated Services Pvt Ltd
- Class Representative till Graduation of MATHEMATHICS dept.
- Lead college sponsored one day workshop on" Recent Trends in Electronics" organized by Department of Electronics Smt. Kasturbai Walchand College, Sangli.
- Won the first prize in Kabaddi Competition in 2004 organized by Shantiniketan College.
- Won the first prize in Kho-Kho Competition in 2004 organized by Shantiniketan College

Personal Profile:

Name: Vijayalaxmi Shetty Dateof Birth: 13/11/1987

Father name: Nandkumar Shetty

Gender: Female

Marital Status: Married

Languages Known: English, Hindi, Marathi and Kannada.

Nationality: Indian

Declaration:

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Vijayalaxmi Shetty